Guide to the Henry Baker, Letterbook
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Letterbook]
1722-1770
OSBORN FC109 1/2
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.39
(1 volume)
Anonymous MS. Collection of copies of 210 letters to and from Baker dating from 1722 to 1770; letters discuss scientific subjects, especially microscopy, electricity, and the education of deaf children; also discuss contemporary affairs, most notably the Jacobite Rebellion (1745-1746) and the London earthquake (1750).
Baker, Henry, 1698-1774
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fc109 1/2. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Electricity; English literature -- 18th century; English poetry -- 18th century; Jacobite Rebellion, 1745-1746; Letters; Microscopy; Great Britain -- Intellectual life -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Baker, Henry, 1698-1774; Blair, Robert, 1699-1746
- OSBORN FC109
  - ARDERON, WILLIAM, 1703-1767
    - 9 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1743-52 (Box 1–2)
      Scope and Contents
      1743 Dec - 1752 Aug
      Norwich
      23 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss a visit by John
      Theophilus Desaguliers (1683-1744).
      109/I/26,42,43,46,80 and
      109/II/128,130,134,145
  - ARDERON, WILLIAM, 1703-1767
    - "A Short Description of the Remains of Sr John Falstafs House in Norfolk": anonymous MS, 1752 (Box 2)
      3 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Memorandum concerning Sir John
      Falstaf (1378?-1459).
      109/II/146
  - BADCOCK, RICHARD
    - Letter (copy) to [Henry Baker (1698-1774)], 1746 Nov 20 (Box 1)
      Twickenham
      2 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Requests names of members of the
      Royal Society of London and
      distinguishes varieties of
      polyanthus.
      109/I/60
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - "Memorandum": anonymous MS, [1762 Dec 1] (Box 2)
      n.p.
      1 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Biographical information on Dr.
      Nathaniel Matthew Wolfe, physician
      to Prince Fryderyk Michal Czartoryski
      (1696-1775).
      109/II/172
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - "Memorandum": anonymous MS, 1770 (Box 2)
      London
      Election and subsequent malfeasance
      of Emanuel Mendes da Costa
      (1717-1791); sale of his collections
      carelessness of James West
      (1704?-1772).
      109/II/175
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - "Memorandum": anonymous MS, [1767] (Box 2)
      [London]
      Attempts to recover his letters to
      the late William Arderon (1703-1767)
      and John Browning.
      109/II/189
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 13 letters (copies) to William Arderon (1703-1767), 1744-52 (Box 1–2)
      1744 Nov - 1752 Jul
      31 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss: Baker's work; the
      Royal Society of London; John Hill
      (1716?-1778); James Harrison
      (1693-1776); and microscopes
      developed by Mr. Page and Lindsay
      also mentions John Montagu (2nd duke
      of Montagu, 1690-1749).
      109/I/32,42,43,46,56,63,76,82,103
      and 109/II/124,135,139,141
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 6 letters (copies) to Archibald Blair, 1746-49 (Box 1–2)
      1746 Nov - 1749 Feb
      16 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss extrasensory
      perception; mention David Erskine,
      9th earl of Buchan (1672-1745),
      Alexander Hume Campbell (1708-1760),
      and George MacKenzie, 1st earl of
      Cromarty (1630-1714).
      109/I/59,64,72,101 and 109/II/114
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Isabella (Law) Blair (1715?-1774), 1746 Mar 10 (Box 1)
      5 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Concerns the death of her husband,
      Robert Blair (1699-1746).
      109/I/55
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 8 letters (copies) to Robert Blair (1699-1746), 1743-46 (Box 1)
      1743 Jun - 1746,
      18 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss: Baker's winning the
      Copley Medal and his "History of the
      Polype"; George Adams; George
      Berkeley, bp. of Cloyne (1685-1753)
      Martin Folkes (1690-1754); Thomas
      Thompson (d.1763); and the death of
      Alexander Pope (1688-1744).
      109/I/16,20,23,28,30,33,39,49
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Benjamin Boddington, [1741 Feb] (Box 1)
      Letter discusses the speech
      production of a young girl with no
      tongue.
      109/I/12
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to William Borlase (1695-1772), 1752 Feb 22 (Box 2)
      On the death of Dr. Cromwell Mortimer
      (d.1752); Thomas Birch (1705-1766)
      elected as successor; also discusses
      proposals by Emanuel Mendes da Costa
      (1717-1791) for a book on fossils.
      109/II/140
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 6 letters (copies) to John Browning, 1746-[1758] (Box 1–2)
      1746 Dec - [1758] Jul
      Letters discuss: the Royal Society
      of London; experiments with
      electricity carried out by Sir
      William Watson (1715-1787); theories
      of John Hill (1716?-1778); the
      classifications of Linneus (Carl von
      Linne, 1707-1778); Peter Camper
      (1722-1789); William Stukeley
      (1687-1765); the death of John
      Montagu (2nd duke of Montagu,
      1690-1749); Richard Wilkes
      (1691-1760); Robert Clayton (Bp. of
      Clogher, 1695-1758).
      109/I/61,87 and
      109/II/116,117,164,165
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 6 letters (copies) to Joseph Lawrence Bruni, [1743]-1747 (Box 1)
      [1743] Dec - 1747 Aug
      14 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss: Abraham Trembley
      (1700-1784); George Anson, baron
      Anson (1697-1762); various electrical
      experiments; and the Jacobite
      Rebellion of 1745-1746.
      109/I/24,31,44,47,54,78
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 2 letters (copies) to Alexander Hume Campbell (1708-1760), 1743-48 (Box 2)
      1743 Sep and 1748 Sep
      Letters discuss a scientific
      monograph by Dr. Gianfrancesco Pivati
      (1689-1764) which was translated by
      David Erskine Baker (1730-1767); also
      discusses experiments with
      microscopes.
      109/II/106
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Peter Collinson (1694-1768), 1768 Apr 9 (Box 2)
      Strand
      Baker will deliver paintings to
      Charles Lyttelton, bp. of Carlisle
      (1714-1768); collections of Emanuel
      Mendes da Costa (1717-1791) will be
      sold ro the relief of bondsmen
      turbulence of supporters of John
      Wilkes (1727-1797).
      109/II/193
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-17445
    - Letter (copy) to Dr. Pierre Demours (1702-1795), 1745 Mar 26 (Box 1)
      Thanks Demours for his translation
      of Baker's "History of the Polype".
      109/I/40
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 8 letters (copies) to Philip Doddridge (1702-1751), 1747-51 (Box 1–2)
      1747 Nov - 1751 Jan
      32 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss: the education of
      deaf mutes; the development of
      Philosophical Societies; the London
      earthquake (1750); the method of
      innoculation proposed by John Ranby
      (1703-1773); also mentions the
      Christmas party given by John
      Montagu, 2nd duke of Montagu
      (1690-1749).
      109/I/ 89,92,95,104 and
      109/II/112,125,131,136
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 2 letters (copies) to Martin Folkes (1690-1754), 1741-50 (Box 1–2)
      1741 Feb and 1750 Mar
      4 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Comments on Benjamin Boddington and
      on the London earthquake of 1750.
      109/I/11 and 109/II/126
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to [Richard Gough (1735-1809)], 1769 Aug 14 (Box 2)
      Baker will try to locate the son of
      Dr. Cromwell Mortimer (ca.1700-1752)
      who is in possession of a MS which
      Gough is seeking.
      109/II/202
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Westley Hall (1711-1776), 1749 Sep 7 (Box 2)
      Discusses Hall's philosophical
      writings; mentions frequent
      appearances of a comet.
      109/II/119
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to [Charles Lyttelton, bp. of Carlisle (1714-1768)], 1767 Nov 25 (Box 2)
      Discusses supposed remains of the
      London residence of Thomas Wolsey,
      cardinal Wolsey (1475?-1530).
      109/II/191
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 13 letters (copies) to Henry Miles (1698-1763), 1743-51 (Box 1–2)
      1743 Nov - 1751 Jan
      30 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss electrical
      experiments, John Hill (1716?-1775),
      Robert Boyle (1627-1691), Francis
      Hawksbee (1687-1763), Sir William
      Watson (1715-1787), Edmund Halley
      1656-1742), John Tuberville Needham
      (1713-1781), Gianfrancesco Pivati
      (1689-1764), and Miles's own proposed
      work on the "History of Electricity"
      also included are drawings by David
      Erskine Baker (1730-1767).
      109/I/22,38,41,50,52,58,85,105
      and 109/I/115,122,137,138
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to George Brudenell Montagu, earl of Cardigan (later 3rd duke of Montagu, 1712-1790), [1752] (Box 2)
      The recipient's father, John Montagu,
      2nd duke of Montagu (1690-1749), had
      admired Baker's "Employment for the
      Microscope" (1753); sends a copy to
      the son who also is interested in the
      subject.
      109/II/144
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 5 letters (copies) to Dr. James Mounsey, 1748-70 (Box 1–2)
      1748 May - 1770 Feb
      22 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss the Royal Society of
      London and the Royal Society of Arts,
      mistaken treatment of the American
      colonies, and poverty and luxury in
      contemporary London; also mentions
      the electric shock of Robert Clayton,
      bp. of Clogher (1695-1768), the death
      of Henry Baker, Jr. (1734-1766), and
      the education of William Baker
      (1763-1828).
      109/I/99 and 109/II/182,188,196,206
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 2 letters (copies) to Pitt Ridgeway, 7th earl of Londonderry (1719?-1765), 1747 (Box 1)
      1747 Sep and 1747 Oct
      Letters discuss scientific projects
      and the spread of a cattle disease.
      109/I/79, 81
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Dr. Stuck, 1752 Aug 18 (Box 2)
      Catharine Street
      Recommends lightning conductor
      invented by Benjamin Franklin
      (1706-1790).
      109/II/143
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to James Symonds, 1745 Sep 24 (Box 2)
      Baker has received the description
      of Symonds's coin collection and
      will aid the recipient in his search
      for duplicates or needed specimens.
      109/II/120
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - Letter (copy) to James Symonds, 1750 Mar 12 (Box 2)
      Discusses the recent earthquakes
      (London earthquake and its
      aftershocks); also includes a list
      of coins for exchange or acquired by
      Thomas Lawrence (1711-1783).
      109/II/127
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 7 letters (copies) to Stephen de Vismes, 1753-70 (Box 2)
      1753 Nov - 1770 Nov
      Letters discuss political affairs in
      England: trouble with the American
      colonies and India; food prices
      Jewish enfranchisement; the ministry
      of Augustus Henry Fitzroy, 3rd duke
      of Grafton (1735-1811); allegations
      of corruption by Samuel Musgrave
      (1732-1780); attempts to clean and
      illuminate London; affairs of Thomas
      Birch (1705-1766) and John Wilkes
      (1727-1797).
      109/II/152,180,186,198,205,207,209
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 3 letters (copies) to Thomas Walls (b.1672), 1739-45 (Box 1)
      1739 Feb - 1745 Mar
      7 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss speech production
      mention John Copping (b.1698),
      William Holder (1616-1698), Vincent
      Browne (1695-1747), John Kippax
      (1682-1760), and Richard Pocock, bp.
      of Meath (1704-1765).
      109/I/6,14,37
  - BAKER, HENRY, 1698-1744
    - 4 letters (copies) to Nathaniel Matthew Wolfe, 1766-69 (Box 2)
      1766 Mar - 1769 Aug
      19 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss Bernard Jussieu
      (1698-1777), James Short (1710-1768),
      John Smeaton (1724-1792), and Joseph
      Planta (1724-1827).
      109/II/183,185,194,201
  - BANNERMAN, PATRICK
    - Letter (copy) to John Cuming, 1747 Aug 20 (Box 1)
      Kinnoul
      Answers to the queries propounded by
      Henry Baker (1698-1774).
      109/I/74
  - BLAIR, ARCHIBALD
    - 7 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1746-49 (Box 2)
      1746 Dec - 1749 Aug
      Gardald
      35 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss instances of second
      sight and extrasensory perception.
      109/I/62,65,69,73,97,108
      and 109/II/118
  - BLAIR, ISABELLA (LAW), 1715?-1774
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1746 Mar 1 (Box 1)
      Athelstaneford
      Death of her husband, Robert Blair
      (1699-1746)
      see Osborn Shelves fc 109/I/55.
      109/I/53
  - BLAIR, ROBERT, 1699-1746
    - 7 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1743-45 (Box 1)
      1743 Jun - 1745 Feb
      13 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss Baker's and Blair's
      works and microscopes; a poem
      entitled "Sacharissa Weeping" is
      also included.
      109/I/15,17,21,27,29,35
  - BODDINGTON, BENJAMIN
    - Letter (copy) to [Henry Baker (1698-1744)], 1741 Feb 4 (Box 1)
      Ipswich
      1 p.; 32 x 21 cn.
      Letter discusses the case of a girl
      whose cancerous tongue falls out.
      109/I/10
  - BORLASE, WILLIAM, 1695-1772
    - 3 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1753-55 (Box 2)
      1753 Oct - 1755 Mar
      6 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss scientific projects,
      the financial difficulties of Emanuel
      Mendes da Costa (1717-1791), and the
      proposed membership in the Royal
      Society of London of Thomas Pennant
      (1726-1798); also mentions Charles
      Lyttelton, bp. of Carlisle
      (1714-1768).
      109/II/150,156,157
  - BROOKE, RICHARD
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1762 Sep 28 (Box 2)
      Maryland
      Sends condolences on the loss of
      Baker's wife, Sophia (Defoe) Baker
      (1705?-1762); discusses dyes and
      samples of dyed cotton which he will
      send.
      109/II/167
  - BROWNING, JOHN
    - 2 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1748-49 (Box 1–2)
      1748 Apr 9 and 1749 Oct
      Burton Hill [Yorks.]
      9 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss cremation and urn
      burial, a description of Stonehenge
      by John Wood (1705?-1754), and
      information on zinc smelting.
      109/I/98 and 109/II/123
  - BUCHAN, DAVID ERSKINE, 9TH EARL OF, 1672-1745
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1727 Aug 11 (Box 1)
      Letter discusses his son's progress
      and sends compliments to Mary
      (Hutton) Worstenholme, lady
      Worstenholme, and John Forster.
      109/I/4
  - CAMPBELL, ALEXANDER HUME, 1708-1760
    - 2 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), [1748]-1748 (Box 1)
      [1748 Feb] and 1748 Sep
      experiments; also mention
      Gianfrancesco Pivati (1698-1764) and
      Sir William Watson (1715-1787).
      109/I/94, 107
  - CLAYTON, ROBERT, BP. OF CLOGHER, 1695-1758
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1747 Jul 3 (Box 1)
      Clogher
      Letters sends thanks for a previous
      letter from Baker and informs Baker
      that the enclosure he sent to
      Clayton has been sent to Thomas
      Walls (b.1672).
      109/I/71
  - COLLINSON, PETER, 1694-1768
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1768 Apr 2 (Box 2)
      Mill Hill
      About a packet for Charles Lyttelton,
      bp. of Carlisle (1714-1768).
      109/II/192
  - COPPING, JOHN, B.1698
    - 3 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1722-23 (Box 1)
      1722 and 1723 [no dates]
      Hammersmith
      Attempts to show Baker's poems to
      Alexander Pope (1688-1744) and
      Thomas Tickell (1686-1740).
      109/I/1,2,3
  - COSTA, EMANUEL MENDES DA, 1717-1791
    - 2 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1763 Jan (Box 2)
      Seeks an appointment to the Royal
      Society of London; mentions Francis
      Hawksbee (1687-1763).
      109/II/174,176
  - CUMING, JOHN
    - Letter (copy) to Archibald Blair, 1747 Jun 20 (Box 1)
      Humby
      12 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Answers Baker's 8 questions about
      second sight with 10 reported
      examples of it.
      109/I/70
  - DODDRIDGE, PHILIP, 1702-1751
    - 10 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1747-50 (Box 1–2)
      1747 Nov - 1750 Oct
      67 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss the London earthquake
      (1750), the Philosophical Society and
      the report to it by William Shipley
      (1714-1803), as well as the Jekyll
      Fund (Sir Joseph Jekyll, 1663-1738)
      included is a monograph on Locusts.
      109/I/86,90,93,100,102,109
      and 109/II/113,129,132,133
  - EARLE, GOODENOUGH
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1749 Jun 7 (Box 2)
      Barton
      Thanks him for his poem of "the
      Universe".
      109/II/110
  - GARDEN, ALEXANDER, 1730-1791
    - 3 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1753-57 (Box 2)
      1753 Dec - 1757 Apr
      Charlestown, S.C.
      24 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss various scientific,
      mostly botanical and zoological,
      projects: mentions many important
      scientific figures, among others:
      John Ellis (1710-1776); William
      Arderon (1702-1767); John Huxham
      (1692-1768); Cadwallader Colden
      (1688-1777); John Bartram (1699-
      1777); Benjamin Franklin (1706-1790)
      John Clayton (1693-1773); Mark
      Catesby (1679-1749); Pehr Kalm (1716-
      1779); Carl von Linne (1707-1778)
      William Shipley (1714-1803); and
      Charles Plumier (1646-1704).
      109/II/158,160,163
  - GARDEN, ALEXANDER, 1730-1791
    - Letter (incomplete copy) to William Shipley (1714-1803), 1755 Apr 5 (Box 2)
      List of crops and commodities
      discusses threshing machines in
      comparison to slave labor.
      109/II/159
  - GOSTLING, WILLIAM, 1696-1777
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1749 Jan (Box 2)
      Canterbury
      Sends his account of a "fireball"
      [meteor] which was seen two years
      earlier in Deal.
      109/II/111
  - GOUGH, RICHARD, 1735-1809
    - 2 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1769-70 (Box 2)
      1769 Aug and 1770 Mar
      Letters discuss a work by Maurice
      Johnson (1688-1755) and a proposed
      "Memoirs of the Society of
      Antiquaries"; a biography of Henry
      Hare, 3rd baron Coleraine (1693-1749)
      is also included.
      109/II/200,208
  - HALL, WESTLEY, 1711-1776
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1769 Aug 24 (Box 2)
      Alnwick. 2 p.; 32 x 21 cm. Discusses two sycamore trees growing around stones fallen from a nearby wall. 109/II/203
  - HANWAY, JONAS, 1712-1786
    - Letter (copy) to [Nathaniel] Forster (1718-1757), 1746 Apr 12 (Box 1)
      St. Petersburg 5 p.; 32 x 21 cm. Letter discusses the "Everlasting Fire" seen near Baku, as well as other natural phenomena. 109/I/57
  - HOPE, HENRIETTA
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), [ca.1765] (Box 2)
      Sends her thanks for his past help and
      kindness with regard to her education.
      109/II/210
  - MILES, HENRY, 1698-1763
    - 11 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1743-56 (Box 1–2)
      1743 Sep - 1756 Dec
      Tooting
      Letters discuss scientific
      experiments, as well as Jean Nicolas
      Sebastien Allamand (1713-1787), John
      Ellis (1710-1776), and Sir Hans
      Sloane, bart. (1660-1753); also
      mentions the Jacobite Rebellion of
      1745-1746.
      109/I/19,34,36,48,51,88 and
      109/II/121,162,153-155
  - MILWARD, EDWARD, 1712-1757
    - Letter (copy) to Dr. Cromwell Mortimer (1700?-1752), 1742 Apr 26 (Box 1)
      Letter discusses the articulation of
      tongueless speakers.
      109/I/13
  - MOUNSEY, JAMES
    - 5 letters (copies) to Henry Baker, [1747]-1762 (Box 1–2)
      [1747] - 1762 Nov, n.p.
      21 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters discuss Mounsey's positions
      as an army physician and court
      physician in Russia; also discusses
      a treatment for rabies, an earthquake
      in Siberia, and introduces the
      rhubarb.
      109/I/77,84,96 and 109/II/166,168
  - PENNANT, THOMAS, 1726-1798
    - 2 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1753-56 (Box 2)
      1753 Oct and 1756 Jan
      Downing
      Letters discuss scientific matters.
      109/II/151,161
  - SHIPLEY, WILLIAM, 1714-1803
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1753 Aug 12 (Box 2)
      Northampton
      Discusses his recent visits to sights
      of "British Antiquity", in particular
      Stonehenge, Wansdyke, and Avebury
      describes the interaction of the
      local residents with the monuments,
      paying special attention in this
      regard to Avebury; also mentions Dr.
      Stephen Hales (1677-1761).
      109/II/149
  - STUART, ALEXANDER
    - Letter (copy) to Henry Baker (1698-1744), 1740 Nov 5 (Box 1)
      Gt. Russell St., Bloomsbury
      Letter discusses a poem on the
      universe which he will hand to the
      Royal Society of London.
      109/I/9
  - WALLS, THOMAS, B. 1672
    - 3 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1744), 1739 (Box 1)
      1739 Jan - 1739 Aug
      Dublin
      Letters discuss Walls' opinions on
      speech production and his methods and
      fees for teaching the deaf.
      109/I/5,7,8
  - WOLFE, NATHANIEL MATTHEW
    - 12 letters (copies) to Henry Baker (1698-1774), 1762-69 (Box 2)
      1762 Dec - 1769 Nov
      54 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Letters describe a tour of Poland
      with Prince Fryderyk Michal
      Czartoryski (1696-1777); mentions
      the death of Augustus III, king of
      Poland (1696-1763); also makes
      medical observations, commenting on
      smallpox vaccinations and rabies.
      109/II/173,177-179,181,184.187,190,
      195,197,199,204